Max Shalom

Incoming Freshman at Baruch College, CUNY

AWARDS

Brooklyn, NY

(917) 291-4902 maxshalom.com max@maxshalom.com

2021

Arista National Honor Society
Archon National Service Society
2020

Pinkerton Science Scholar National AP Scholar

SKILLS

Fluent in: English and Hebrew

Programs: Proficient in web development, data science and analysis, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Python basics, and other programming language basics

EXTRACURRICULARS

- 1. Robotics Team
- 2. Audio/Visual Squadron
- 3. Masterpiece Theater
- 4. Drone Club

PROJECTS

Website - Allura Imports Inc: Currently designing and developing an intuitive website for Allura Imports Inc., a children's clothing manufacturer. The website includes animations, an email newsletter, and a contact form, all developed by myself with industry-standard developer tools.

Research on Stock Trading Algorithms: Developed a functional algorithm able to trade securities automatically based on 50 and 200-day moving averages and backtest on historical data during my pursuit of learning about this.

EDUCATION

Yeshivah of Flatbush Joel Braverman High School

Graduated: June 2021, Cum Laude | GPA: 91

Relevant Coursework: AP Economics, Regents Algebra I & II, Regents Geometry, AP Statistics, AP Environmental Science, AP Computer Science, Business Law, Intellectual Property, Web Design

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Chesed Mission — *Israel*

Visited hospitals, assisted in food pantries, mentored at-risk youth, and more during my school's winter break.

Sephardic Community Alliance — *Media Team*

MARCH 2020 - OCTOBER 2021

Responsible for all YouTube content and the editing of many hundreds of recorded classes throughout the year to be shared and distributed online.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lucky21 Partners, Roselle, NJ — Content Manager

JUNE 2021 - AUGUST 2021

Responsible for receiving supply orders from manufacturers to our warehouse and implementing them into our massive Amazon e-commerce storefronts. Used data analysis to track inventory and support our buyers.

NYU Tandon School of Engineering — Research Assistant, Chunara Lab

JUNE 2020 - AUGUST 2020 | https://maxshalom.com/arise/

Populations in low socioeconomic communities and geographies usually have a higher burden of cardiovascular diseases (CVDs). Using the National Health Interview Survey (NHIS), I was able to explore public data using industry–standard data science tools and programming languages to find which social factors were most vital in the contraction of a CVD and how to isolate these issues to effectively lower their contraction rate.

ACE Mentorship Program, New York, NY — *Intern*

NOVEMBER 2017 - MAY 2018; NOVEMBER 2018 - MAY 2019

Worked with Mechanical, Electrical, and Engineering (MEP) firm, JB&B, to design a new building for the Ellis Island Ferry Terminal in Battery Park from the MEP viewpoint of the project

Worked with Structural Engineering firm, Thorton Tomasetti, to outline a column placement and beam layout for a fitness center commissioned to be built as part of Cornell Tech's new campus on Roosevelt Island